Ugly Naked Guy is decorating his tree.
裸体的丑男人在装饰他的树
You should see the size of his Christmas balls!
天啊 你该瞧瞧他圣诞球的大小
How much did you tip the super?
你们今年给管理员多少红包？
We were gonna give 50, but we don't wanna look bad.
是啊，我们打算给50 不过我们不想显得比你们小器
This year we made him cookies.
今年我们送他自己做的饼干
And 25 it is.
那就包25块好了
You gave cookies?
你们送他饼干？
Money is so impersonal.
给钱太见外了
Cookies says someone cares.
饼干表示我们关心他
We're broke, but cookies do say that.
好吧，我们没钱 但饼干也能表达这个意思
I can see that.
我了解
A plate of brownies told me a limerick.
曾有盘巧克力糕对我打过油诗
Pheebs,let me ask you something. Were these "funny" brownies?
菲比，请问你 那些巧克力糕有问题吗？
Not especially.
还好啊
But I think they had pot in them.
你知道吗？我想那里面有大麻
So who else did you tip with cookies?
两位，你们还送了谁饼干？
The mailman,the super....
邮差，管理员…
And the newspaper delivery guy.
还有那个送报纸的
Oh,my God.
天哪
What?
怎么了？
You're not gonna like this.
你们可能不会高兴看到这个
These are cookies smashed to the sports section.
天哪，饼干糊在运动版呢
He did my crossword puzzle.
看，在我的字谜那里也是
Yeah,but not very well,unless 14 across,"Gershwin musical"...
对，但是错误百出，除非 横十四的“葛许温音乐剧”…
...actually is "Bite me, bite me,bite me."
是叫“咬我，咬我，咬我”
The One With Phoebe's Dad
-=BT之家DRM小组 http://bbs.btbbt.com=- 河马压缩制作 本字幕为河马根据R3DVD OCR得来
-=BT之家DRM小组 http://bbs.btbbt.com=- 六人行 第2季 第09集 菲比的爸爸
I can't believe it's Christmas already.
真不敢相信圣诞节又到了
One day you're eating turkey, the next thing you know...
我们才刚吃完了感恩火鸡…
...Iords are a-leaping and geese are a-laying.
转眼呢 现在又到了呆鹅下蛋的圣诞节
Which is why geese are so relaxed this time of year.
所以每年的这个时候 鹅才会感觉到很轻松
Hey,guys.
各位
Hey,Rach.
瑞秋
I got you a little present.
我买了一个小礼物给你
I'll open it.
我来拆
It's a Slinky!
是个小司令
Remember?
记得吗？
Walks downstairs Alone or in pairs
什么走下楼梯，单独或成双
Everyone knows it's
大家都知道是…
Just a big spring.
只是一个大弹簧
You're still mad because of the whole
好吧，你还在生我的气 就为了…
Horrible list of reasons not to be with me?
那张不跟我在一起的理由的 可恶单子？
How about we just call it the "unfortunate incident"?
从现在起我们称那为 “那不幸的事件”怎么样？
Hey,Gunther. You got stairs in your place?
阿刚，你家里有没有楼梯？
Go nuts.
去疯吧
Hey,guys.
各位
What's in the bag?
袋子里有什么？
Some presents.
只是些礼物啦
Come on,show us what you bought.
快拿出来瞧瞧啊
You know you want to.
少装了
This is a picture frame from Ben to my parents.
好吧，你们看 这是班送给我父母的相框
Oh,that's cute.
很可爱
Some "Hers" and "Hers" towels for Susan and Carol.
我买“她的”跟“她的”毛巾 给苏珊跟凯洛
And I got this blouse for Mom.
还有，买了这件衬衫给妈
Ross,that is gorgeous!
罗斯，好漂亮哦
Look at these authentic fake metals!
瞧瞧这些假徽章
Mom's gonna be voted "best dressed"...
妈会像在“伪军校”里面…
...at the make-believe military academy!
…会得到 “最佳服装奖”的菲菲
Happy "Christmas Eve" Eve.
圣诞前夕的前夕快乐
Oh,my God! Where did you get this?
我的天哪，这哪儿来的？
Macy's,third floor, home furnishings.
梅西百货三楼，家饰部
This is my father!
这是我爸爸
This is a picture of my dad!
这是我爸爸的照片
That's the guy that comes in the frame.
菲比，那是相框附送的相片
No,it's my dad. I'll show you.
不，这是我爸爸 好，我拿给你们看
I thought your dad was in prison.
菲比，我以为你爸在牢里
No,that's my stepdad.
不，那是我继父
My real dad's the one that ran out on us before I was born.
我真正的爸 是我出生以前就跑了的那个
How have you never been on Oprah?
你怎么会没上过谈话秀啊？
Look,see? This is him.
瞧，这就是他
My mother gave me this picture before she died. Same guy!
我妈在死前给了我这张照片 同一个人来的
This is a picture of the frame guy...
这是一张相框模特儿…
...posing in front of a blue screen with a collie.
…跟一只柯利狗 站在浅蓝背景前的照片
It's not a blue screen. It's just....
那不是蓝背景，那是…
Maybe it was just really clear that day.
也许那天万里晴空吧
Okay,I have to talk to my grandmother.
我得跟我奶奶谈一谈
Wait a minute,honey!
等一下，菲比
I'm trying to get my boss's ex-wife to sleep with me.
我在设法 弄我老板的前任老婆上床
But when Phoebe has a problem, everyone's all ears!
菲比有问题时大家都洗耳恭听
Esther Livingston.
李爱瑟
Gone!
嗝屁了
Hi,Pooh.
丫头
Hi,Gram. What you doing?
奶奶，你在干嘛？
Just updating the phone book.
我在改电话簿
Gram?
奶奶？
Can I see the pictures of my dad again?
我可以再看一次 我爸的照片吗？
Sure,sure.
当然，当然了
How come?
为什么？
Just,you know,to see him.
我只是突然想看一看
Sure. Here.
好，来
This is the one of your father in a meadow.
这是你爸站在草地上的照片
And helping a little boy fly a kite.
他…帮一个小男孩放风筝
And here he is at a graduation.
这一张是他的毕业典礼
Another graduation.
再一张的毕业典礼
再来一张毕业典礼
Is this really my father?
他真的是我爸爸吗？
Is it really your fa?
他真的是你爸…？
Well,of course it is.
天哪，他当然是
I smell smoke. Maybe because someone's pants are on fire!
我看这很有问题 或许有人在说谎
In all the years we've been grandmother and granddaughter...
我们两个当祖孙这么多年了…
...you've never lied.
…你从没有对我撒过谎
All right,that's not your father. It's a picture of a guy in a frame.
好吧，他不是你爸爸 他只是一个相框里的男人
Oh,God.
天啊
It was your mother's idea.
那是你妈的主意
She didn't want you to know your real father...
她不想让你知道谁是你爸…
... because he hurt her so much.
…因为他的离去让你妈很伤心
I didn't want to do it.
我本来也不想跟着她骗你
But then she died and it was harder to argue with her.
可是她死了 那样跟她争辩就太难了
Not impossible,but harder.
不是不可能，只是更难
All right. So he's not a famous tree surgeon?
那他不是一个有名的树医罗？
And I guess he doesn't live in a hut in Burma where there's no phones?
他也不住在 没有电话的缅甸茅屋里头罗？
Last I heard,he was a pharmacist somewhere upstate.
我听说他在纽约州 某个地方当药剂师
That makes no sense.
那没有道理
Why would the villagers worship a pharmacist?
村民干嘛去崇拜一个 药剂师呢？
Honey.
亲爱的
Anyway,that's all I know.
反正呢，我所知道的就这么多
That...
还有…
...and this.
…跟这个
This...
这…
...is the real him.
…是真正的他了
I remember my father all dressed up in the red suit...
我记得我爸爸 他穿了一身火红的衣服…
...the big black boots and the patent leather belt...
…黑色的大靴子 还有漆皮皮带…
...sneaking around downstairs. He didn't want us to see him...
…在楼下鬼鬼崇崇的 他不想被任何人发现…
... but he'd be drunk,so he'd crash into something and wake everybody up.
…可是他醉得摇摇晃晃 然后撞东撞西把大家都吵醒
That doesn't sound like a very merry Christmas.
听起来不像是个快乐的圣诞节
Who said anything about Christmas?
谁说是圣诞节来着？
Anyone hear from Phoebe yet?
有没有菲比的消息？
No,nothing.
没有
I hope she's okay.
希望她没事
I know exactly what she's going through.
是呀，我完全了解她的处境
How do you know that?
你怎么会完全了解她的处境？
She told us.
她告诉我们的嘛
What do you got there,Monica?
摩妮卡，你买了什么？
Stuff for the party.
派对要用的东西
Aren't you guys supposed to be shopping?
你们还在这里干嘛 你们不是该去买礼物了吗？
You didn't buy presents yet?
你们礼物还没买好吗？
Tomorrow's Christmas Eve! What are you gonna do?
明天就是圣诞夜了 你们要怎么办？
Don't you have to be Claymation to say that?
不是黏土动画里面的人 才会那么说的吗？
I don't think the mailman liked your cookies.
对了，摩妮卡 我想邮差不欣赏你的饼干
The ornaments your mom sent.
这是你妈寄来的装饰品
Maybe the mailman liked the cookies. We just didn't give him enough.
说不定他喜欢我的饼干 只是他嫌少了
Monica,pigeons learn faster than you.
摩妮卡，鸽子都学得比你快
Hey,Rach.
瑞秋
I think I know what will make you feel better.
我想我知道 怎么样让你好过点了
How about you make a list about me?
你列张关于我的清单如何？
Forget it. I'm not gonna stand here...
什么？算了吧，罗斯 我怎么会…
...and make a list
…去列一张关于你的…
Okay,you're whiny...
好，我告诉你…
...you are obsessive, you are insecure...
…你爱发牢骚，爱钻牛角尖 没有安全感…
...you're gutless.
…你根本就没种
You don't ever just "seize the day."
你从来不知道怎么把握时机
You liked me for a year and you didn't do anything about it.
你暗恋我多久了？一年 结果你一个屁也没放
And you wear too much of that gel in your hair.
还有，你头发涂了太多发胶了
See,there....
瞧…
All right,you did what I said.
你听我的了
And you know what? You're right. I do feel better.
对呀，你知道吗？ 你说得对，我觉得好多了
Thank you,Ross.
谢了，罗斯
Yeah,in Albany. Could I have the number of Frank Buffay?
麻烦你查一查巴法尔的电话
Okay. In lthaca?
以奇卡呢？
All right,Saratoga?
好吧，沙拉托加？
Oneonta?
翁尼昂塔？
You know what? You shouldn't call yourself lnformation!
好吧，你知道吗？ 你没有资格自称查号台
Hello,Grandma. If that is, in fact,your real name.
奶奶 请问这是不是你的真姓名？
Come on now,Pooh. Don't still be mad at me.
好了，丫头，别跟我生气了
-How's it going? -Not so good.
进行得怎么样了？ 不太好
Upstate's pretty big. He's pretty small. You do the math.
纽约州蛮大的，他蛮小的 你自己算吧
Well,I think you're better off without him.
我想没找到他对你还比较好
Oh,honey,I know he's your daddy.
我知道他是你爸爸
But to me,he's still the irresponsible creep...
但是对我而言…
...who locked up your mom and stole her Gremlin.
…他是那个让你妈怀孕 又偷她的车子，不负责的混球
I know. I just wanted to know who he was,you know?
我知道啊 只是想知道他是谁而已
Yeah,I know.
是啊，我知道
I wasn't completely honest with you when I said I didn't know...
我说我不知道他住在哪里…
...exactly where he lived.
…是有点骗你
What do you mean?
什么意思？
He lives at 74 Laurel Drive in Middletown.
他住在米德城罗瑞街74号
If you hit the Dairy Queen, you've gone too far.
要是看到黛莉冰淇淋就过头了
You can take my cab.
开我的车去吧
Thank you.
谢了
-Nobody else drives that cab. -Got it.
我的计程车别让别人开啊 知道了
I'm gonna see my dad!
我要见到我爸爸了
Thank you.
谢谢
Wish me luck,Grandpa.
好吧，祝我好运了，爷爷
Phoebe here with the cab yet?
菲比开计程车来了吗？
Yeah,she brought the invisible cab.
来了，那是一辆隐形车
Hop in!
上车吧
She'd better get here. The stores close at 7.
她最好快一点 服饰店七点就关门了
It'll be two hours to Phoebe's dad's house...
安啦，我想菲比去她爸那儿 大概两个小时…
...they'll meet,chat, swap life stories.
…他们见面，聊天 交换生活故事
We'll have plenty of time.
还有很多时间的
Hey,here she comes!
她来了
Can you believe this?
你们相信吗？
In,like,two hours I'm gonna have a dad.
再两个小时我就有爸爸了
Yeah,big stuff!
是呀，大事哦
Okay,let's go!
对呀，走吧
Here,you have to hold this.
好，你来拿着这个
"Brake,left. Gas,right"?
左刹车，右加速？
That's my cheat sheet.
对，我的小抄
-Where's my seat belt? -There isn't one.
安全带呢？ 你那边没有了
The paramedics had to cut through it.
被救护人员剪开了
Come on,just tell me. Please,please!
告诉我嘛，拜托…
For the 16th time: No,I do not think you're obsessive!
这是第十六次了： 不，我不认为你钻牛角尖
-It's hot in here! -Rach,get the heat.
天哪，这里怎么这么热啊 麻烦把暖气关小
Ross,turn the heat down,please?
罗斯，把暖气关小
The difference between obsessive
两个之间是有差别…
Ross,the heat!
罗斯，暖气
Okay! Heat,heat,heat! And I'm the obsessive one?
好，暖气…还说我钻牛角尖？
This way is on.
好吧，往这边是开
So this is...
往这边是…
...off.
…关
Did you just break the radiator?
你是否把暖气机弄坏了？
No,I was turning the knob and...
没有，我不过是转了开关…
... here it is.
…结果就掉了
Well,put it back!
那就装回去啊
It won't go back.
装不回去了
I'll call the super.
我打电话给管理员
Here,let me try.
来，我来试试
That's right. I forgot about your ability to fuse metal.
对了 我忘了你融合金属的能力了
Hey,it's Funny's cousin...
好笑的相反…
... Not Funny!
…不好笑
Hi,Mr. Treeger?
崔先生？
It's Rachel Greene from upstairs.
我是楼上的林瑞秋
Yes,somebody broke our knob on the radiator...
对，有人弄坏 我们暖气的开关了…
...and it's really hot in here.
…我们这里好热
Yes,it's hot enough to bake cookies.
对，热到可以烤饼干了
Could we have a new one by 6?
你想你能在六点以前换好吗？
Tuesday? We can't wait until Tuesday.
什么？不，不，星期二 我们等不到那个时候
We're having a party tonight.
我们今晚有派对
Okay,tip the man.
好吧，给他小费
If he doesn't like our cookies,too bad.
不，不喜欢 我们的饼干就算了吧
I won't be blackmailed.
我才不要任人勒索呢
Look,if it gets a little warm...
这里有点热…
...it can be a theme party.
…就改成主题派对好了
Here's a theme: "Come on in,live like bacon!"
这下有主题了： “请进，像热窝上的蚂蚁吧”
This is it!
就是这里了
Seventy-four.
74号
So that's what this is for!
长途跋涉为这个
This is it. I'm gonna meet my dad.
就是这里了 我要见到我爸爸了
This is like the biggest thing ever.
这真是前所未有的大事
Sure is.
说得没错
Here I go. I'm going in.
好了，我要进去了
All right!
好啊
Good luck,Pheebs.
一切顺利哦
Here I go.
好了，我走了
我走了
I'm going.
我要走了
Welcome to our tropical Christmas party.
欢迎光临我们的热带圣诞派对
Put your coats,sweaters, pants and shirts in the bedroom.
外套，毛衣，长裤跟衬衫 请放在卧室里面
It's hard to tell because I'm sweating...
我在冒汗，所以看不出来…
... but I use exactly what the gel bottle says.
…但我完全遵照 瓶上指示的用量
An amount about the size of a pea. How can that be too much?
一颗豆子大小的份量而已 那怎么会太多呢？
Ice?
冰块？
Ice? Ice squares anyone? Take a napkin.
谁要冰块？拿张餐巾
Monica!
摩妮卡？摩妮卡？
Your guests are turning into jerky.
你的客人都快变成人干了
Really? I'm perfectly comfortable.
真的？我觉得舒服得很
Hey! Get in line,buddy. I was next.
排队呀，兄弟，换我了
Mr. Treeger.
崔先生
You said there was a party.
你说有派对啊？
Well,hey,welcome to our sauna.
欢迎光临三温暖
Is it hot? My body always stays cool.
很热吗？我从来不觉得热
Probably because I have so much skin.
说不定是因为我皮肤多了
Hey,cheese!
起士
Here's the chance. Monica,give him cash.
好吧，好吧，机会来了 摩妮卡，给他现金
Rachel,give him your earrings. Something. Anything!
瑞秋，把你的耳环给他 快啊，任何东西都给他
No,I will not cave.
不，我不屈服
I'm with Mon.
对，我也是
All right. You know how you say I never seize the day?
好吧… 你说我从不把握机会？
Even though he's your super, I'm seizing.
他虽然是你们的管理员 我也要把握一下
Mr. Treeger?
崔先生？
Here is $50. Merry Christmas.
这里是50块钱，圣诞快乐
I didn't get you anything.
我没有准备你的礼物
Here's five back.
送你5块钱好了
No,that's your Christmas tip.
不，那是你的圣诞红包
Do you think there's a chance you can fix that radiator now?
你认为你可不可以 现在把暖气给修好？
No can do. Like I told the girl...
没办法，我已经说过了…
... I can't get a knob until Tuesday.
…星期二才拿得到新的开关
Ross?
罗斯？
He's playing baseball.
看来他很僵硬哦
You mean hardball?
你要说强硬吗？
Whatever.
随便啦
What you gonna do?
你打算怎么样呢？
Excuse me. I'm seizing.
抱歉，我要把握一下
Mr. Treeger?
崔先生？
Here's another 50.
我再给你五十
Happy Hanukkah.
祝你圣诞节快乐
Will this help with the knob-getting?
这样我们是不是 可以拿到新的开关了呢？
No,the place is not open till Tuesday.
不行 那家店星期二才会开门
Am I not saying it right?
我的发音不标准吗？
So you really did like my cookies?
你真的喜欢我的饼干吗？
Yeah,they were so personal. It really showed you cared.
是呀，那好温暖哦 真的表示你的关心
Nice seizing...
把握得好…
...gel boy.
…发胶兄
Is this mistletoe?
这是w寄生，没错吧？
No,that....
不，那个叫…
That is basil.
…叫九层塔
If it was mistletoe, I was gonna kiss you.
如果是w寄生，我就要亲你了
No,it's still basil.
不，那还是九层塔
Chestnuts roasting on an open fire
火炉上烤栗子
Jack Frost nipping at your nose
雪人在啃你的鼻子
-How far did you get? -Mailbox.
你走到哪里啊？ 信箱
All right,we're getting closer.
有进步了
What's going on?
菲比，你怎么了？
It's just like a whole mess of stuff.
其实原因很多啦
Like yesterday,my dad was this famous Burma tree-surgeon guy.
昨天，我爸爸他还是一个 名闻遐迩的缅甸树医
And you know,now he's a pharmacist guy and....
可是他现在 却变成一个药剂师了…
Well,maybe he's this really cool pharmacist guy.
或许他是一个 很酷的药剂师也说不定
Yeah,maybe! And I'll knock on the door...
对，或许，对 然后我会跑去敲他的门…
...and he'll hug me, and I'll have a dad!
…他会拥抱我，我会有个爸爸
I'll go to his pharmacy and everyone will be nice to me...
然后大家都会亲切地对待我…
... because,you know, I'm Frank's daughter.
…因为我是法兰的女儿
So why not go knock?
那就快去敲门哪
Because,I mean,what if he's not this great-dad guy?
因为如果他没有那么棒呢？
What if he's still the dirtbag who ran out on my mom and us?
如果他还是那个 抛妻弃子的浑球呢？
You know what?
你知道吗？
I've already lost a fake dad this week.
我这个礼拜 已经失去一个假爸爸了
I don't think I'm ready to lose a real one.
我不想再失去一个真的爸爸
Pheebs,that's okay. You took a big step today.
菲菲，没关系啦 你已经跨了一大步了
Someday,when you're ready, you'll make it past the hedges.
有一天当你准备好的时候 你就会越过那片篱笆了
And when you do, he'll be lucky to have you.
那个时候他会有幸得到你
You guys....
你们…
Sorry about your shopping.
抱歉，你们来不及购物了
Oh,that's okay. We'll figure something out.
没关系，会有办法的
I know you're not going in there...
我知道你不要进去…
... but you think it's okay if I go in and use his bathroom?
…不过你想我可不可以进去 跟他借一下洗手间？
That's fine,never mind.
没关系，算了
Cool,snow!
酷耶，下雪了
Kind of like a blank canvas.
像空白的画布
Ho-ho-ho-holy crap, is it hot in here!
这里面好热啊
You mind if I turn the heat down?
介意我把暖气关小吗？
We could have used that kind of thinking earlier!
我们怎么都没想到呢
So,Pheebs,how did it go?
菲菲，结果怎么样？
Oh,I couldn't go in.
我没有办法进去
-Honey,I'm sorry. -Are you okay?
好可惜喔 你还好吗？
Yeah,it's okay, because I know he's there.
好，没关系 因为我知道他在哪儿
So that's enough for now.
现在只要那样就够了
Hey,it's after midnight! Merry Christmas,everyone!
各位，过了十二点了 祝大家圣诞快乐
Oh,right! Merry Christmas!
圣诞快乐
The knob was broken...
开关坏了…
...so I turned it off from underneath. I hope that's all right.
…所以我从下面关掉了 希望不会有问题
Rach,these are for you.
瑞秋，送你的
Wiper blades!
汽车雨刷
I don't even have a car.
我连车都没有
No,but with this new-car smell, you'll think you do!
对呀，但加上这个芳香剂 你会以为你有
Okay,Pheebs,your turn.
菲菲，换你了
Toilet-seat covers!
马桶纸垫啊
Is that what you did while I got gas?
我去加油的时候 你们就去买这个吗？
You guys!
你们两个真好！
And for Ross...
至于罗斯…
... Mr. Sweet Tooth.
…甜食先生
You got me a cola drink?
你们送我一瓶可乐？
And a lemon-lime!
还有柠檬莱姆饮料
Well,this is too much! I feel like I should get you another sweater.
简直太…太厚礼了吧 我应该再送你们一件毛衣
And last,but not least....
还有一个很有价值的…
They're ribbed for your pleasure!
加纹让你更有快感